<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Radha Soami</string>
    <string name="radha_soami">Radha Soami</string>
    <string name="share_app">Share App</string>

    <string name="about_us">About Us</string>
    <string name="about_us_text">Radha Soami Satsang Beas (RSSB) along with its international affiliates is a spiritual organization based on the teachings of all religions and dedicated to a process of inner development under the guidance of a spiritual teacher.In the Indian language, Radha Soami means ‘lord of the soul’, satsang describes a group that seeks truth, and Beas refers to the town near which the main centre is located in northern India. There are a number of other contemporary movements that use the name ‘Radha Soami’ but Radha Soami Satsang Beas is not associated with any of them. \n\n RSSB was established in India in 1891 and gradually began spreading to other countries. Today RSSB holds meetings in more than 90 countries worldwide. It is a non-profit organization with no affiliation to any political or commercial organizations.\nThe basis of every religion is spirituality. With the passage of time and changing social values, the basic spiritual teachings often become embellished with extra rules and rituals, and eventually take the shape of a formal religion. Despite its extensive outreach activities, RSSB tries to maintain the integrity of its spiritual core and preserve the simplicity of its teachings. At the heart of the RSSB teachings is a belief that there is a spiritual purpose to human life – to experience the divinity of God who resides in all of us. It is through this experience that we will realize the truth of the concept that there is only one God and we are all expressions of his love.\n\n Central to the RSSB teachings is a spiritual teacher who explains the purpose of life and guides and instructs members in a method of spirituality based on a daily meditation practice. The present teacher is Baba Gurinder Singh, who lives with his family at the main centre in northern India. By performing the meditation practice according to the teacher\'s instructions, individuals can realize the presence of God within themselves. It is a solitary practice that is done in the quiet of one\'s own home. Members commit themselves to a way of life that supports spiritual growth while carrying out their responsibilities to family, friends and society. There are no rituals, ceremonies, hierarchies or mandatory contributions, nor are there compulsory gatherings. Members need not give up their cultural identity or religious preference to follow this path.\n\nTo build on the primary spiritual practice of meditation, members are vegetarian, abstain from alcohol, tobacco, and recreational drugs, and are expected to lead a life of high moral values. A vegetarian diet encourages respect and empathy for all life and acknowledges that there is a debt to be paid for taking any life unnecessarily. Abstaining from intoxicants improves ones ability to concentrate and calms the mind during meditation. Members are encouraged to be self-supporting and not be a burden on society. They are free to make their own choices in life and maintain any cultural or religious affiliations they choose. RSSB does not involve itself in the personal lives of its members.\n\nInherent to the Society’s philosophy is the importance of seva, meaning selfless service, or voluntarism. Voluntary service is the backbone of all activities connected with RSSB. All administrative functions, construction of Indian and international centres, feeding of the hundreds of thousands of visitors who visit the headquarters in India, writing and translating books and magazines explaining the teachings, are done by members on a voluntary basis. Mahatma Gandhi embodied the importance of service in his statement: “The best way to find your self is to lose yourself in the service of others.” It is believed that through service, one loses one\’s sense of self-importance and becomes humble. That is the foundation of a spiritual life.</string>

    <string name="rate_us">Rate Us</string>
    <string name="overview">Overview</string>
    <string name="youtube">Radha Soami Youtube</string>
    <string name="bhajans">Bhajans</string>
    <string name="education">Education</string>
    <string name="photos">Photographs</string>
    <string name="punjabi">Punjabi</string>
    <string name="hindi">Hindi</string>
    <string name="english">English</string>
    <string name="dera_jaimal">Dera Baba Jaimal Singh</string>
    <string name="overview_1">RSSB\'s main centre is Dera Baba Jaimal Singh, named after its founder who settled there in the late 1800’s. Located in Punjab, India, the ‘Dera’ is a self-contained community with both administrative and residential facilities. Although the centres throughout the world are affiliated with RSSB India, each country\'s administration is autonomous, with a Board of Management that operates under a standard constitution modified to comply with local laws and conditions. Administration is handled entirely by volunteers, and operations are funded through unsolicited donations. The organization does not engage in any fundraising activities.\\n\\nThere are more than 5,000 RSSB centres throughout India, and internationally RSSB-affiliated organizations hold meetings in more than 90 countries. Meetings are held in rented halls, community centres or RSSB-owned properties. The purpose of these gatherings is to explain the RSSB philosophy. The meetings are non-denominational and open to the public. No fees are charged and there is no advertising or proselytizing.</string>
    <string name="dera_lib">Dera Library</string>
    <string name="overview_2">RSSB has a publishing department that has produced more than 70 original titles on spirituality. Volunteers have translated a large selection of these books into 35 languages. A 20,000 square-metre library at the main centre in India will eventually house a collection of nearly 500,000 volumes concentrating on world religions, mysticism, philosophy and related subjects. The library will be open to scholars and researchers of all faiths.</string>
    <string name="beas_hospital">Beas Hospital</string>
    <string name="overview_3">In order to consolidate RSSB’s medical outreach and health initiatives, it has set up a sister organization, the Maharaj Jagat Singh Medical Relief Society, which operates three rural charitable hospitals: in Beas, Punjab; Sikanderpur, Haryana; and in Bhota, Himachal Pradesh. All three hospitals function as primary care facilities with fully functioning medical departments such as: ophthalmology, orthopaedics, gynaecology &amp;amp; obstetrics, ENT, surgery &amp; anaesthesia, paediatrics, radiology, and dental. All medical services, including medicine and in-patient care are provided free of charge. The Beas Hospital is the largest hospital with 260 beds and treats on average 1,200 patients each day through its Outpatient Department (OPD). The Sikanderpur Hospital has 50 beds, the Bhota Hospital has 75 beds, and each treats about 450 patients each day through their Outpatient Departments. The large number of OPD patients is a reflection of the limited number of medical facilities in these rural farming communities. No distinction is made as to the background of the patients, either in regard to their economic status, social standing, or religious affiliation.\n\nWhile the focus of the path is spiritual, centred on an internal meditation practice, at the same time members are encouraged to volunteer their free time in seva (service), voluntary service to others regardless of religion, caste or colour. In this context, RSSB has supported disaster relief efforts in a number of emergency situations, building multi-purpose community shelters and housing. These include the Gujarat earthquake of 2000, the Kashmir earthquake of 2005, Leh cloudbursts and landslides of 2010, and the Nepal earthquake of 2015.\n\nThe Main Centre\nDera Baba Jaimal Singh is a mini-township with 7,000 residents. Since the Dera is the home of the spiritual leader of the organization, large crowds visit on specially designated weekends to hear his discourses. These crowds average between 200,000 to 500,000 people depending on the season. The administration has become highly skilled in managing and providing facilities for large numbers of people on a short-term basis.</string>
    <string name="satsang_venue">The Satsang Venue</string>
    <string name="meeting_venue">Dera meeting venue</string>
    <string name="overview_4">In order to provide a sheltered satsang venue for these gatherings, the Dera’s engineering department has constructed one of the largest covered structures in Asia, designed and fabricated on site using a lightweight space-frame technology. The roof provides a covered area where up to 500,000 people can be seated, and which can easily be expanded as the need arises. A computerized digital audio system was specially designed for the venue to provide the best possible sound for such a challenging environment.</string>
    <string name="food">Food</string>
    <string name="dera_langar">Dera langar</string>
    <string name="overview_5">To feed the visitors three meals a day, several approaches are taken. The langar (a place where food is served free of charge) is the primary means. The free langar complex covers over 48 acres and operates around the clock. Capable of feeding up to 300,000 people per meal, 50,000 in a single sitting, it has a mostly volunteer staff who prepare and serve simple but nourishing food suitable to local tastes. As an example, the langar annually cooks more than 350,000 kilos of rice and uses more than 2.6 million kilos of wheat to make the traditional flat breads. Meals are also served at canteens and snack bars at a nominal price.</string>
    <string name="shelter">Shelter</string>
    <string name="overview_6">The Dera seeks to be as self-sufficient and environmentally friendly as possible. Every year thousands of trees are planted. Many lawns and parks beautify the colony and provide space for visitors and residents to rest and relax. More than 1,250 acres of land are cultivated for growing vegetables and fruits that are used in the langar and by Dera residents. Organic farming methods are being adapted to local conditions. The Dera has its own water supply, water treatment plant and solid waste treatment facility. It has its own electrical sub-station and large electrical generator back-up facility to supply emergency power to the whole community. In addition, the Dera generates 19.5 megawatts (peak) electricity from photovoltaic (solar) panels mounted on the rooftops of eight large sheds.</string>
    <string name="dera_guest_hostel">Dera guest hostels</string>
    <string name="overview_7">The colony is visited by people from around the world and all walks of life. To provide temporary accommodations for everyone, a variety of facilities are offered, all free of charge. There are a number of guest hostels with individual rooms and attached baths, hostels with dormitory-style rooms, and other large buildings to house visitors.</string>
    <string name="the_community">The Community</string>
    <string name="dera_school">Dera Pathseekers School</string>
    <string name="overview_8">The Pathseekers School is a recent project established for the benefit of the children of Dera residents and the staffs of the Dera and Beas hospitals. It currently serves approximately 850 students from the primary to secondary levels. The school is professionally run and equipped with up-to-date laboratories and computers, and offers a full range of arts, sports and academic programs. The students receive a well-rounded education – up to India’s Certified Board Education standard.</string>
    <string name="soami_ji">Soami ji</string>
    <string name="sawan_singh">Maharaj Sawan Singh Ji</string>
    <string name="jagat_singh">Maharaj Jagat Singh Ji</string>
    <string name="charan">Maharaj Charan Singh Ji</string>
    <string name="gurinder">Baba Gurinder Singh Ji</string>
    <string name="download">Download</string>
    <string name="download_link">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.radhasoamisatsangbeas</string>
    <string name="satsang_schedule">View Satsang Schedule</string>
    <string name="background">Background</string>
    <string name="edu_1">The RSSB Educational &amp; Environmental Society is a registered society with its headquarters at Dera Baba Jaimal Singh, Beas, Punjab. Under the aegis of this society, Pathseekers School was started on 1 April 2014 with 570 students in Pre-primary and Primary wings in different classes. This number has now grown to around 900 and is likely to reach around 1200 by 2019–20, when the school will include class XII. The students are children of sevadars and employees of Dera and the hospitals in Beas, Bhota and Sikanderpur. The school is spread out over an area of about 38 acres and is affiliated with the Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE).\n\nThe school is headed by a Principal, who is assisted by two Headmisstresses, each one overseeing the Pre-primary/Primary and Middle/Secondary classes. There is a highly competent and dedicated group of 89 teachers of various disciplines, supported by a team of 87 people managing the school. All school staff are provided with housing in Dera free of cost.</string>
    <string name="vision">Vision</string>
    <string name="edu_2">The vision at Pathseekers is to provide a secure and enabling environment that supports the creation of good human beings by imparting value-based education. The culture aims to promote values of love, respect, compassion, patience and tolerance.\\n\\nRecognizing that each child learns differently and at his/her own pace, the curriculum offers a wide range of learning opportunities through games and sports, carpentry, pottery, weaving, art and craft, drawing, cooking, music, dance and drama. It equips children with the skills and abilities that will prepare them for life.\\n\\nThe exposure to experiential learning helps the childen to become self-aware, independent thinkers, capable learners, confident and informed decision makers. This inquiry-based approach ensures that learning happens beyond the four walls of the classroom. These experiences aim to be inviting, engaging and challenging for all children. A life-skills program, value education and co-curricular activities are interwoven into all classes across all grades.</string>
    <string name="curriculam">Curriculum and Teaching Methodology</string>
    <string name="edu_3">As children learn by inquiry, research and experience; the school follows an inquiry based approach. The curriculum is integrated across basic subjects of English, Math, Science, Social Science, Hindi and Punjabi. Visual and Performing Arts and Information and Communication Technology (ICT) are used to explore themes and are also independent subjects for exploration.</string>
    <string name="classroom">Classrooms</string>
    <string name="curriculam_primary">Curriculum for Pre-Primary Wing</string>
    <string name="edu_4">The curriculum aims to make the child’s learning enjoyable and comfortable. It is designed to nurture young children and stimulate their language, physical, cognitive, and creative development and encourage positive self-esteem and social interaction. It is designed to meet the individual needs of each child, emphasizing the building of autonomy and problem-solving abilities in the following areas: music and movement, environment and nature, language, gross and fine motor coordination, creative arts, story and dramatic play, physical development, creative development, and outdoor play.</string>
    <string name="curriculam_middle">Curriculum for Primary and Middle Wings</string>
    <string name="edu_5">A project-based approach is followed where the child learns individually or in groups and builds experience. Children are encouraged to explore and acquire new skills. Children learn in a realistic environment or in real-life situations and are encouraged to raise questions and find answers to these questions through various methods.</string>
    <string name="teaching_method">Teaching Methodology for Pre-Primary Wing</string>
    <string name="edu_6">The school follows a thematic approach by interweaving a project approach and is based on the following points:\\n\\n1. Children need large blocks of uninterrupted time to explore activities and master new skills. When children play, they use their imagination and develop creativity.\\n\\n2. Children develop fine motor skills by working with puzzles, crayons, markers, play dough and boards.\\n\\n3. Children experience cause and effect by building up blocks and knocking them down, using sand and water (measuring, pouring, etc.), and rolling cars.\\n\\n4. Teachers help children\'s language development by reading to them, singing simple songs with movement and encouraging their participation.</string>
    <string name="teaching_method_middle">Teaching Methodology for Primary and Middle Wing</string>
    <string name="edu_7">Various new and effective methods of teaching are used to make learning enjoyable. Concepts are taught using a blend of role play, group discussion, quizes, dramatics, poetry, puzzles, presentations, videos, educational games, etc. The school offers varied activities in special rooms: logico-mathematical, music, dance and drama, language lab, art and craft, drawing, the Little Chef program (cooking), weaving, carpentry and pottery. (Sculpture, photography, robotics, and music are additional activities for the Middle Wing.) The school has structured the timetable so that all children engage in co-curricular activities, such as arts, sports, and carpentry, within school hours, along with academic subjects.</string>
    <string name="assessment">Assessment</string>
    <string name="edu_8">The assessment aims to evaluate students’ abilities in real-world contexts. In other words, students learn how to apply their skills to authentic tasks and projects. Assessment is carried out in three ways: Diagnostic or pre-assessment, Formative assessment, and Summative assessment.</string>
    <string name="parent_participation">Parent Participation</string>
    <string name="edu_9">Parents play a very important role in a child\'s development, so they are included in the activities of the school. There is a system for regular feedback to parents on their child’s performance. Parents are also involved on a voluntary basis for community support to the students and school. Parent-teacher meetings provide a forum for building rapport between teachers and parents and for regular communication about a student\'s progress. These meetings are conducted every month.</string>
    <string name="excursions">Excursions and Field Trips</string>
    <string name="edu_10">Pathseekers believes in exploration of knowledge rather than the imparting of mere facts. Field trips are an integral part of the school activities and curriculum. Educational excursions help children build experience and learn by observing and exploring.</string>
    <string name="field_trips">Field Trips</string>
    <string name="celebrations">Celebrations</string>
    <string name="edu_11">Children are made aware of cultural diversity and how to respect it for community bonding. Religious festivals and national and international days are celebrated. The essence of the festivals is told through stories, music, dance and drama, food, discussions and a variety of hands-on activities.</string>
    <string name="character_building">Character Building</string>
    <string name="edu_12">Weekly lessons on divinity, values and life skills help to nurture and develop children to become responsible citizens. Value education is included in all academic and co-scholastic disciplines in the regular lesson plans. There is a daily 20-minute assembly, at which the school prayer, current affairs, and a thought of the day are regular features.</string>
    <string name="morning_assembly">Morning assembly</string>
    <string name="house_system">School House System</string>
    <string name="edu_13">The house system at Pathseekers aims to give students a sense of identity and pride in a supportive and secure environment. The school is divided into four sub-units called \'houses\' and each student is assigned to a particular house. Houses may compete with one another at sports and maybe in other ways, thus providing a focus for group loyalty. The houses encourage positive competition and a closer rapport between students and teachers. This helps new staff and students adapt to the culture of Pathseekers School.</string>
    <string name="school_building">School Buildings</string>
    <string name="edu_14">All buildings are air-conditioned and designed to promote a learning environment. Classrooms are spacious and furnished with modern flexi-furniture to suit new teaching methods. There are four main buildings for Pre-primary, Primary, Middle and Secondary wings. Each is designed, furnished and equipped with furniture and equipment suitable for the specific age group. The school has 50 classrooms, audiovisual rooms, offices, an IT room, an infirmary, four multipurpose halls, a dining hall, activity rooms, an indoor stadium, an outdoor open-air stadium, and a gymnasium. Work centres promote student creativity. The school has well- equipped laboratories for science, languages, social studies, maths and vocational education.\\n\\n   Staff rooms and teachers’ work stations take care of the needs of the educatators. Use of information and computer technology (ICT) in teaching and learning interactions is highly promoted. It is facilitated by a state-of-the-art computer laboratory, computer-technology-enabled classrooms and a modern audiovisual language laboratory.</string>
    <string name="pathseeker_school">Pathseekers School</string>
    <string name="lang_lab">Language lab</string>
    <string name="comp_lab">Computer lab</string>
    <string name="hobby">Hobby Centres</string>
    <string name="edu_15">The school has a dedicated team of trainers and teachers who guide the children in music, dance and drama, weaving, art and craft, cooking (the Little Chef program), sculpture and carpentry.</string>
    <string name="music">Music classes</string>
    <string name="dance">Dance and drama classes</string>
    <string name="weave">Weaving classes</string>
    <string name="craft">Art and craft classes</string>
    <string name="little_chef">Little chef</string>
    <string name="sculpture">Sculpture classes</string>
    <string name="carpenter">Carpentry workshop</string>
    <string name="lib">Library</string>
    <string name="edu_16">There is a reading corner in every classroom so that students develop a taste for reading. The school has a well-stocked library with a separate section for students and teachers in every wing. The library is stocked with fiction and nonfiction, reference books, newspapers and magazines. Story-reading sessions are held in the library. There are about 15,000 books of different genres on a variety of subjects. Children are encouraged to use the library and its resources for research and study from morning till evening in their free periods or allotted library periods. In addition to this, primary and pre-primary classes have class libraries to attract children to the world of books.</string>
    <string name="special_education">Special Education and Counselling</string>
    <string name="edu_17">The school is proactive towards students’ special-education and psychological needs. There is a separate Special Education Needs department with suitable classrooms and two full-time counsellors and two dedicated special educators. Every child is unique and has a right to be educated and prepared for life. Students with special needs are admitted and their special requirements in terms of infrastructure, curriculum and activities are taken care of. There is a team of special-education teachers who prepare special curricula for children’s specific needs, and their abilities are developed in regular classrooms where they mingle with other children. Along with this, individual sessions are also conducted.\\n\\nThere are well-qualified health and wellness teachers, who provide counselling to the students as well as to the parents. Counselling sessions aim at developing self-esteem and building confidence in their ability to handle their problems and redirect their behaviour.</string>
    <string name="central_dining">Central Dining Hall</string>
    <string name="edu_18">Since nutrition is an integral part of growth and development, there is close coordination between the Central Dining Hall management and the Bhojan Bhandar (the Dera’s restaurant) as well as with medical personnel. A tasty, nutritious and balanced diet is provided to all. The dining hall can accommodate 600 students at a time. Mid-morning breakfast, lunch, and evening milk is served to students and staff on all working days.</string>
    <string name="labo">Laboratories</string>
    <string name="edu_19">As already mentioned, information and communications technology is highly promoted and facilitated by a state-of-the-art computer laboratory, computer-technology-enabled classrooms, and a modern audiovisual language laboratory. In addition, there is a language lab, mathematics lab, composite lab and a robotics lab, where students attempt to create their own human-friendly robots.</string>
    <string name="compo_lab">Composite Lab</string>
    <string name="robo_lab">Robotics Lab</string>
    <string name="best_practise">Best Practices</string>
    <string name="edu_20">Some of the best practices at Pathseekers are:\\n\\n1. Qualitative holistic education based on the unique character of each child\\n\\n2. Community engagement and learning for life\\n\\n3. Cross-integration of curriculum\\n\\n4. Differentiated teaching\\n\\n5. Inquiry-based interdisciplinary projects\\n\\n6. Vocational education\\n\\n7. Democratic students’ governance\\n\\n8. Activity-based learning\\n\\n9. 100% participation in all domains</string>
    <string name="student_well">Student\'s Health and Well Being</string>
    <string name="sport_complex">Sports Complex</string>
    <string name="edu_21">Sports have always been viewed as a way to stay healthy and fit, but their importance goes much further. Participating in sports teaches life lessons like discipline, responsibility, self- confidence, accountability, and teamwork. Studies have shown that exercise increases blood flow to the brain and helps the body build more connections between its nerves, leading to increased concentration and enhanced memory. It stimulates creativity and develops problem- solving skills. In short, playing sports helps your brain grow and makes it work better.\\n\\nFrom a social standpoint, sports are a powerful tool that brings people together and create a sense of community. They develop connections that bond together people from all walks of life. Pastimes such as internet, television and computer games can make children sedentary and increase the risk of obesity. Participation in school sports provides a sense of belonging and being part of a team or group. Engaging in sports reduces the amount of unsupervised free time and prevents boredom.</string>
    <string name="playing_field">Playing Fields and Sports Activities at Pathseekers</string>
    <string name="edu_22">The school campus includes three large playing fields where children can play, exercise and practise. An expansive Sports Complex, including a track, has been added that meets international standards. All playing fields are properly watered and maintained by expert gardeners. School grounds are also used for celebrating various functions and an annual sports day.\\n\\n   The school has high-quality equipment and trainers for table tennis, volleyball, basketball, cricket, athletics, hockey, football, yoga, gymnastics, and roller skating, as well as a modern gymnasium for senior students. At Pathseekers sports activities begin for students as young as toddlers. The same spirit continues through primary, middle and secondary grades.</string>
    <string name="yoga_tod">Yoga classes for toddlers</string>
    <string name="sack_race">Sack race - Kindergarden students</string>
    <string name="sports_period">Sports period - Nursery students</string>
    <string name="edu_23">In addition to physical education classes during the school day, Pathseekers holds after-school sports for primary school students consisting of gymnastics, yoga, volleyball, skating, and high and long jump, to name a few. The goal is for students to develop self-esteem, enabling them to achieve their highest potential and to imbibe the school’s vision and mission.</string>
    <string name="gym_pri">Gymnastics classes for Primary students</string>
    <string name="yoga_pri">Yoga classes for Primary students</string>
    <string name="football_middle">Football coaching - Students from Primary and Middle wings</string>
    <string name="basket">Basketball</string>
    <string name="judo">Judo Training</string>
    <string name="hockey">Hockey Training</string>
    <string name="badminton">Badminton</string>
    <string name="edu_24">Our aim is to develop students’ enthusiasm and interest in physical activity, and then to encourage them to participate regularly during their time at Pathseekers. We hope that this exposure to a wide range of physical activity at Pathseekers School will encourage pupils to continue with regular physical activity later in life.</string>
    <string name="gym">Gymnasium</string>
    <string name="annual_sports">Annual Sports Meet</string>
    <string name="banner_ad">ca-app-pub-2450844335946572/8247211131</string>
    <string name="messages">Messages</string>

</resources>
